<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deploying Your App on GA JavaScript</title>
    <link>/17-deploying-your-app/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Deploying Your App on GA JavaScript</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/17-deploying-your-app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Objectives</title>
      <link>/17-deploying-your-app/objectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/17-deploying-your-app/objectives/</guid>
      <description> Deploy a JavaScript-based application using Github Pages, Surge or Heroku
 Learn how to secure sensitive credentials in a &amp;ldquo;non node-based&amp;rdquo; front-end application
 Deploy your final projects the approach that best fits your application&amp;rsquo;s needs
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Pages</title>
      <link>/17-deploying-your-app/github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/17-deploying-your-app/github-pages/</guid>
      <description> What is Github Pages?  GitHub Pages is a static site hosting service designed to host your personal, organization, or project pages directly from a GitHub repository
 GitHub Pages is a static site hosting service and doesn&amp;rsquo;t support server-side code such as, Express (via Node JS), Ruby, Python or PHP
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Along: Host App using Github Pages</title>
      <link>/17-deploying-your-app/code-along-host-app-using-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/17-deploying-your-app/code-along-host-app-using-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>Code Along: Host App using Github Pages  Together we&amp;rsquo;ll walk through the process of hosting a static application, an application that does not have a server (i.e. Express), on Github Pages  Instructions 1. Find Traffic Light project Using your operating system&amp;rsquo;s finder / explorer application, copy your Traffic Light application (project name: traffic-light) application from a lesson earlier in the course folder to your lesson_17 folder
 If you do not have a working version of traffic-light you can clone down a working version here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surge</title>
      <link>/17-deploying-your-app/surge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/17-deploying-your-app/surge/</guid>
      <description> What is Surge?  An alternative to Github pages
 Best used for Static websites
 Simple to deploy
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Along: Host App using Surge</title>
      <link>/17-deploying-your-app/code-along-host-app-using-surge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/17-deploying-your-app/code-along-host-app-using-surge/</guid>
      <description>Code Along: Host App using Surge  Together we&amp;rsquo;ll walk through the process of hosting a static website / application (that does not have a backend server like Express) using Surge  Instructions 1. Install the surge package on your computer  Run the following from your command line (from any folder location) to install surge globally on your computer
$ npm install --global surge   
2. Run surge from the Traffic Light project folder  Navigate to the project folder of the Traffic Light application from the Github Pages Code Along</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>